### YENSAN NGUYEN

# **SKILLS**

- C# programming
- Java programming
- JavaScript programming
- Krotlin programming (Learning)
- Bash ( weak ) ( willing to learn )
- HTML
- CSS
- SQL
- React.js
- Node.js
- jQuery
- REST API
- MongoDB

### **TOOLS**

- Git
- Visual Studio
- Visual Studio Code
- IntelliJ IDEA
- Android Studio (Learning)
- Word
- Excel
- PowerPoint

## **HOBBIES**

- Building fantasy world
- Taking walks
- Reading
- Fighting games
- Designing fictional character
- Learning guitar

**Location**: Pierrefonds, QC **Email** : Yensannguyen@gmail.com

**Tel**: (514) 716-6557 **Languages**: English, French and Vietnamese

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Dynamic, with a great sense of detail, as well as a quick learning curve, I offer the most interesting versatility for a company like yours. It is with great motivation that I ponder this tech job. This work will also allow me to acquire professional skills and experiences.

#### **EDUCATION**

### College diploma

John Abbott College

Program: Computer Science (420.B0)

### High school diploma

École Saint-george

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Ben & Florentine 2021

3555 Saint-Charles Blvd, Kirkland, Quebec H9H 3C4

- Busboy / Host: Cleaning tables, Interact with customers, assist kitchen staff
- Dishwasher: Clean kitchen, Organize plates, Washing plates and utensils

Zento Sushi 2022 - 2023

475 Grand Boulevard, local 7, L'Île-Perrot, QC J7V 4X4

• Sushi chefs: Prepare ingredients, Can make 5 different sushi

### Ongles Memoires

475 Grand Boulevard, local 8, L'Île-Perrot, QC J7V 4X4

• Receptionist: Maintaning / Updating Website, Manage appointment, Clean the salon

### WORK HABITS AND SKILLS

- Adapts well to change
- Highly organized and professional in approach
- Creative decision-maker
- Works effectively within a team and fosters positive relationship

2019 - (expected graduation: May 2024)

2014 - 2019

2023

Email: Yensannguyen@gmail.com Tel: (514)-716-6557 Name: Yensan Nguyen

**PROJECTS** 

**Project NewWorld** 

Personal, Hobby, Long-term, Javascript, RPG Maker Engine

I recently started a personal project from scratch using the RPG Maker Engine as a base. My goal is to create a large game using this engine to gain a better understanding of how the RPG genre works. Eventually, I plan to use this

knowledge to undertake another project using Unity.

Quiz Maker

School-work, Full-control, C#, Visual Studio, Wpf

This is a project with the goal of applying all the knowledge I've gained during the first, second, and third semesters of my computer science studies at John Abbott College. The project involves creating a quiz app that reads a text file

to generate and play quizzes. Users will also have the option to save their scores if they choose.

What I learned: How front-end and back-end works, OOP

**Fruit Review Website** 

School-work, Team project, MongoDB, Javascript, Html, React, Visual Studio Code

The project aimed to teach me how to create a website while utilizing a database and collaborating as part of a team. The project involved developing a fruit review website where users could submit reviews and ratings for specific

fruits. One of the most valuable skills I acquired during this project was learning how to effectively manage time,

plan, and conduct peer reviews as part of a team rather than working independently.

What I learned: Scrum, NoSQL, User authentications, Cookies, REST API, HTTP method, Documentation

REFERENCE

Provided on request

Page 2 of 4

### YENSAN NGUYEN

# **COMPÉTENCE**

- Programmation C#
- Programmation Java
- Programmation JavaScript
- Programmation Krotlin ( en train d'apprendre)
- Bash (faible) (prêt à apprendre)
- HTML
- CSS
- SQL
- React.js
- Node.js
- jQuery
- REST API
- MongoDB

# **OUTLIS**

- Git
- Visual Studio
- Visual Studio Code
- IntelliJ IDEA
- Android Studio ( en train d'apprendre )
- Word
- Excel
- PowerPoint

## **LOISIRS**

- Créer un monde imaginaire
- Promenades
- Lire
- Jouer aux jeux de combat
- Créer des personnages fictifs
- Apprendre la guitare

Lieu: Pierrefonds, QC Email: Yensannguyen@gmail.com

**Tel**: (514) 716-6557 **Languages**: Français, Anglais et Vietnamien

#### OBJECTIF DE CARIÈRRE

Dynamique, possédant un grand sens du détail, ainsi qu'une rapide d'apprentissage, j'offre une polyvalence des plus intéressantes pour une compagnie comme la vôtre. C'est avec une grande motivation que j'envisage d'occuper cet emploi. Ce travail me permettra aussi d'aquérir des compétences et expériences proffesionelles .

#### **FORMATIONS**

### Diplôme d'études collegial

2019 - (Graduation prévue: 2024)

John Abbott College

Programme: Technique de l'informatique (420.B0)

### Diplôme d'études secondaire

2014 - 2019

2023

École Saint-george

#### EXPÉRIENCE PROFESSIONNELLE

Ben & Florentine 2021

3555 Saint-Charles Blvd, Kirkland, Quebec H9H 3C4

- Aide serveur / Hôte : Nettoyer les tables, interagir avec les clients, aider les personnels de cuisine
- Plongeur : Nettoyer la cuisine, Organiser les assiettes, Laver les assiettes et les ustensiles

Zento Sushi 2022 - 2023

475 Grand Boulevard, local 7, L'Île-Perrot, QC J7V 4X4

• Chef de sushis : Préparer les ingrédients, peut préparer 5 sushis différents

Ongles Memoires
475 Grand Boulevard, local 8, L'Île-Perrot, QC J7V 4X4

• Réceptionniste : Maintenance / Mise à jour du site internet, Gestion des rendez-vous,

Nettoyage du salon

Tel: (514)-716-6557 Email: <u>Yensannguyen@gmail.com</u> Nom: Yensan Nguyen

### HABITUDES DE TRAVAIL ET HABILETÉS

- Bonne adaptation au changement
- Créative envers mes décisions

- Travaille efficacement au sein d'une équipe et favorise des relations positives
- Être organisé et se présenter de manière professionnelle

#### **PROJETS**

### **Projets NewWorld**

Personnel, Passe-temps, Long terme, Javascript, RPG Maker Engine

J'ai récemment commencé un projet personnel en partant de zéro et en utilisant le moteur RPG Maker comme base. Mon objectif est de créer un jeu de grande échelle à l'aide de ce moteur afin de mieux comprendre le fonctionnement du genre RPG. Par la suite, j'envisage d'utiliser ces connaissances pour entreprendre un autre projet en utilisant Unity.

### Créateur de quiz

Travail scolaire, Contrôle total, C#, Visual Studio, Wpf

L'objectif de ce projet est d'appliquer toutes les connaissances que j'ai acquises au cours du premier, deuxième et troisième semestres de mes études d'informatique au John Abbott College. Le projet consiste à créer une application de quiz qui lit un fichier texte pour générer et jouer des quiz. Les utilisateurs auront également la possibilité de sauvegarder leurs scores s'ils le souhaitent

Ce que j'ai appris: Comment fonctionne le front-end et le back-end, OOP

### Revue des fruits

Travail scolaire, Projet d'équipe, MongoDB, Javascript, Html, React, Visual Studio Code

Le but de ce projet était de m'apprendre à créer un site web tout en utilisant une base de données et en collaborant au sein d'une équipe. Le projet consistait à développer un site web d'évaluation de fruits où les utilisateurs pouvaient soumettre des critiques et des évaluations pour des fruits spécifiques. L'une des compétences les plus précieuses que j'ai acquises au cours de ce projet a été d'apprendre à gérer efficacement mon temps, à planifier et à mener des évaluations par les pairs au sein d'une équipe plutôt que de travailler de manière indépendante.

Ce que j'ai appris: Scrum, NoSQL, Authentification des utilisateurs, Cookies, API REST, Méthode HTTP, Documentation.

### **RÉFÉRENCE**

Fourni sur demande